Guide to the Arthur Frederick and Mary Clabaugh Wright Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1932-1977; Series I; 9.5
  - Sung project, undated (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - T, 1934-1965 (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - T, 1966-1976 (Box 14, Folder 192)
  - Toronto session, undated (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Twitchett, Denis, 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Twitchett, Denis, 1960-1964 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Twitchett, Denis, 1965-1969 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Twitchett, Denis, 1970-1975 (Box 15, Folder 197)
  - U, 1960-1975 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - University of Washington, 1950-1954, 1964-1969 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - V, 1957-1972 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - W, 1951-1965 (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - W, 1966-1976 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Wechsler, Howard J., 1964-1966 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Wechsler, Howard J., 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Wechsler, Howard J., 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - Wechsler, Howard J., 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - Whitman College, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - Winks, Robin, 1962-1965 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A., 1949-1951 (Box 15, Folder 209)
  - Wright, Arthur: career data, 1947-1976 (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - Wright, Arthur: memorials, 1976-1977 (Box 16, Folder 211)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, dissertation, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, manuscripts
    - Buddhism in China, undated (Box 16, Folder 213)
    - ChIang-an, undated (Box 16, Folder 214)
    - Changan: Chinese Capital and Asian Cosmopolis, undated (Box 16, Folder 215)
    - The Chinese Sense of the Past, undated (Box 16, Folder 216)
    - Confucianism in Action: a Report on Some Studies, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 217)
    - The Cosmology of the Chinese city, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 218)
    - The Cosmology of the Chinese City, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 219)
    - Historiography in Chinese civilization, undated (Box 17, Folder 220)
    - History of Man, China to c. 1400, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 221)
    - History of Man, China to c. 1400, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 222)
    - History of Man, China to c. 1400, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 223)
    - History of Man, China to c. 1400, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 224)
    - On Chinese Urban History: Its Status and Potential, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 225)
    - On the Spread of Buddhism to China, undated (Box 17, Folder 226)
    - Propaganda and Persuasion in Imperial China, undated (Box 17, Folder 227)
    - Propaganda and Persuasion in Imperial and Contemporary China, undated (Box 17, Folder 228)
    - The study of Chinese civilization, undated (Box 17, Folder 229)
    - The study of Non-Cognate civilizations: Liberating Effects, undated (Box 17, Folder 230)
    - The Sui Dynasty, undated (Box 18, Folder 231)
    - The Sui Dynasty, undated (Box 18, Folder 232)
    - The Sui Dynasty, undated (Box 18, Folder 233)
    - The Sui Dynasty, undated (Box 18, Folder 234)
    - Sui Legitimation: Formal Procedures, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 235)
    - Sui Wen-ti: Portrait of a Great Reformer Sui-Wen-ti Reconsidered, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 236)
    - Symbolism and Function: Reflections on Changan and Other Great cities, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 237)
    - The T'ang World, undated (Box 19, Folder 238)
    - The T'ang World, undated (Box 19, Folder 239)
    - T'ang T'ai-tsung: The Man and the Persona, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 240)
    - Two continental Reunifiers: sui Wen-ti and Charlemagne, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 241)
    - The writing of Chinese History: An Enlarged Perspective, undated (Box 19, Folder 242)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, popular lectures, 1950-1960 (Box 19, Folder 243)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, popular lectures, 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 244)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, popular lectures, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 245)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, popular lectures, undated (Box 19, Folder 246)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, popular lectures, undated (Box 19, Folder 247)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 248)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1950s (Box 19, Folder 249)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 250)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1962-1965 (Box 20, Folder 251)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 252)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 253)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, 1974-1977 (Box 20, Folder 254)
  - Wright, Arthur: writings, printed copies, undated (Box 20, Folder 255)
  - Wright family, 1932-1934 (Box 20, Folder 256)
  - Wright family, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 257)
  - Wright family, 1936 (Box 20, Folder 258)
  - Wright family, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 259)
  - Wright family, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 260)
  - Wright family, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 261)
  - Wright family, 1940 1941 (Box 21, Folder 262 263)
  - Wright family, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 264)
  - Wu, Nelson, 1960-1964 (Box 21, Folder 265)
  - Y-Z, 1957-1972 (Box 21, Folder 266)
  - Yale delegation to China, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 267)
  - Yale Faculty Seminar on Chinese and Comparative Historiography
    - General, undated (Box 21, Folder 268)
    - General, undated (Box 21, Folder 269)
    - General, undated (Box 21, Folder 270)
    - Wright, Arthur, 1970 September (Box 21, Folder 271)
    - Bielenstein, Hans, 1970 October (Box 22, Folder 272)
    - Zimmerman, James H., 1970 October (Box 22, Folder 273)
    - Hsii, Cho-Yiin, 1970 October (Box 22, Folder 274)
    - Lee, Thomas H. C., 1970 October (Box 22, Folder 275)
    - Twitchett, Denis C., 1970 October (Box 22, Folder 276)
    - Somers, Robert, 1970 November (Box 22, Folder 277)
    - Watson, Burton, 1970 November (Box 22, Folder 278)
    - Chan, H. L., 1970 December (Box 22, Folder 279)
    - Schwartz, Benjamin I., 1970 December (Box 22, Folder 280)
    - Gay, Peter, 1970 December (Box 22, Folder 281)
    - Freeman, Michael, 1971 February (Box 22, Folder 282)
    - Chan, H. L., 1971 February (Box 22, Folder 283)
    - Wright, Arthur, 1971 February (Box 22, Folder 284)
    - Brockman, Susan N., 1971 March (Box 22, Folder 285)
    - Yang, Lien-Sheng, 1971 March (Box 22, Folder 286)
    - Nivison, David, 1971 April (Box 23, Folder 287)
    - Wu, Silas, 1971 April (Box 23, Folder 288)
    - Rogers, Michael, 1971 April (Box 23, Folder 289)
    - Zimmerman, James H., 1971 April (Box 23, Folder 290)
    - Twitchett, Denis, 1971 May (Box 23, Folder 291)
    - Franke, Herbert, 1971 May (Box 23, Folder 292)
  - Yale University Press, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 293)
  - Yamazaki, Hiroshi, 1955-1967 (Box 23, Folder 294)
  - Yap, Pow-Meng, 1957-1959 (Box 23, Folder 295)
  - Unidentified, 1937-1966 (Box 23, Folder 296)
- Course and Research Files, circa 1947-1976; Series II; 15
  This series is arranged in two sections: Courses and Research topics. The section Courses is arranged in alphabetical order by course title. Material for which the course number is indicated, but no course title given, appears at the end of the section. The material in Research topics is arranged in alphabetical order by topic.
  - Courses
    - Chinese historiography: graduate seminar (Hist. 256) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Chinese historiography: graduate seminar (Hist. 256) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Chinese historiography: graduate seminar (Hist. 256) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Chinese historiography: graduate seminar (Hist. 256) (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Chinese history: survey course (Hist.113) (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Chinese history: survey course (Hist. 113) (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Chinese history: undergraduate seminars (Hist. 245, 248, 271) (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Comprehensives and minor field exams and reading lists (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - History of China: graduate seminar (Hist. 346) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - History of the civilizations of Eastern Asia (Hist. 113) (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Intellectual history of the Far East (Hist. 192) (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Modern Chinese history (Hist. 191) (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Modern Chinese history (Hist. 191) (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Modern Chinese history (Hist. 191) (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Modern Chinese history (Hist. 24) (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Problems in Chinese history (Hist. 253) (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a, 252a) (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Social and intellectual history of China (Hist. 45a) (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - (Hist. 114) (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - (Hist. 195a) (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Research topics
    - Bad last rulers (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Biography (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Biography (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Buddhism (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Buddhism (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Buddhist bibliography (Box 27)
    - Buddhist terms and bibliography (Box 28)
    - Carolingian notes (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Chiang an (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Chiang an (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Chiang an, Sui, or T'ang illustrations (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Chinese artwork and artifacts (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Chinese Buddhism (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Chinese civilization (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Chinese eremitism (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Chinese historiography (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Chinese historiography (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Chinese historiography (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - Chinese history (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - Chinese history (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - Chinese history (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - Chinese history (Box 31)
    - Chinese history (Box 32)
    - Chinese history (Box 33)
    - Chinese texts (Box 34)
    - Cities (Box 35, Folder 50)
    - Cities (Box 35, Folder 51)
    - Communist China (Box 35, Folder 52)
    - Communist China: value change (Box 35, Folder 53)
    - Communist China: values, attitudes (Box 35, Folder 54)
    - Confucianism (Box 35, Folder 55)
    - Ethnolinguistics (Box 35, Folder 56)
    - Fu I (Box 35, Folder 57)
    - Fukuyama articles (Box 35, Folder 58)
    - Gunavarman (Box 35, Folder 59)
    - Han Wu-ti (Box 35, Folder 60)
    - Hegel (Box 35, Folder 61)
    - Historiography (Box 35, Folder 62)
    - History of Chinese Buddhism (Box 35, Folder 63)
    - History of Chinese Buddhism (Box 36, Folder 64)
    - Intellectual history (Box 36, Folder 65)
    - Intellectual history (Box 36, Folder 66)
    - Intellectual history (Box 36, Folder 67)
    - Intellectual history (Box 36, Folder 68)
    - Intellectual history (Box 36, Folder 69)
    - Japan (Box 36, Folder 70)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 36, Folder 71)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 36, Folder 72)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 36, Folder 73)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 37)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 38)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 39)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 40)
    - Kao Seng Chuan (Box 41)
    - Language and culture (Box 42, Folder 74)
    - Ming dynasty (Box 42, Folder 75)
    - Mo-chi Shan (Box 42, Folder 76)
    - Mythology of East and West (Box 42, Folder 77)
    - Religion (Box 42, Folder 78)
    - Romanization (Box 42, Folder 79)
    - Sinological methods (Box 42, Folder 80)
    - Slavery in China (Box 42, Folder 81)
    - Sui (Box 42, Folder 82)
    - Sui legitimation (Box 42, Folder 83)
    - Sui studies (Box 43, Folder 84)
    - Sun Yat-Sen (Box 43, Folder 85)
    - Symbols of imperial power (Box 43, Folder 86)
    - T'ai-tsung (Box 43, Folder 87)
    - T' ang- (Box 43, Folder 88)
    - T'ang (Box 43, Folder 89)
    - T'ang (Box 43, Folder 90)
    - T'ang (Box 43, Folder 91)
    - T'ang Buddhist festivals (Box 43, Folder 92)
    - Total culture patterns (Box 44, Folder 93)
    - Translation (Box 44, Folder 94)
    - Tung-huang fragments (Box 44, Folder 95)
    - Values (Box 44, Folder 96)
- Additional material, Accession 2001-M-014
  - "An Inquiry Into the Socio-Religious Character of Chinese Civilization with Special Reference to Those Features Conducive to the Acceptance of Buddhism," by Arthur F. Wright, 1937 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The ch'ing-t'an of the Wei and Chin Periods" [an essay comprising chapter VII of Liu Ta-chieh's Wei Chin ssuhsiang lun, presumably annotated by A. F. Wright], 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Zenryu Tsukamoto to A. F. Wright, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Chinese history, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional material, 1928-1982; Accession 2008-M-047
  Correspondence and topical files (unbound) are arranged by personal name and roughly chronologically therein. There is an overlap of types of materials. Correspondence folders may contain related printed material; conversely, folders of topical files may have some correspondence. Bound photocopies of these items (nineteen volumes) are arranged chronologically by compilers.
  Scope and Contents
  This accession comprises original correspondence and photocopies thereof; genealogical research and family documents; newspaper clippings; writings; and photographs relating primarily to Arthur Frederick Wright and Mary Clabaugh Wright, as well as their respective families and associates. The materials, in unbound and bound formats, document the personal lives, and to a lesser extent, the professional interests and careers of the Wrights. Of particular interest are materials related to their internment as prisoners of the Japanese in a camp for enemy aliens in Wei-hsien, China, from March 1943 to October 1945. Researchers should also consult Series I, Correspondence and Topical Files, of the original accession, which contains similar materials.
  - Wright, Arthur Frederick
    - Correspondence
      - Family and friends re trip to Japan, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Fuchs, Walter, 1941-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Heissig, Walther, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Wright, Jonathan A. and C. Duncan Wright (sons), 1973 August 4, 1974 June-October (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Wright, Mary Clabaugh, 1967 January-March (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Topical files
      - Condolences and memorials received at the death of Mary Clabaugh Wright, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
      - Lithograph for The National Cyclopedia of American Biography, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Memorial service program of Arthur F. Wright, 1976 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Wright, Mary Clabaugh
    - Correspondence
      The majority of correspondence is between Mary Clabaugh Wright and her parents, primarily her father. Folders may contain related printed material.
      - 1928-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1934 Jan-Jul (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - 1934-1938 (Vassar years) (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1937-1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 1940-1941 Aug (Box 2, Folder 3)
        "Mary's Letters From Japan 1940-1941"
      - 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        Includes correspondence of the Wrights and family and friends regarding internment of MCW and AFW in China.
      - 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        Correspondence of others with family and government officials regarding Wrights' internment in China.
      - 1944-1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 1944-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        "Round Robin" letters describing world trip.
      - 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Fisher, Harold, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Get well wishes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Stanford University Press, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Unidentified, 1967, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Topical files
      - College papers for history and philosophy classes, 1934-1940 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
      - Memorial service program and obituaries for MCW, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Oliver family history, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Wei-hsien Camp, Circa 1940-1943 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        Includes articles and reports on camp conditions.
      - Miscellaneous, 1945 November 11 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clabaugh, Samuel Francis (father of MCW)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1936, 1945, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Marriage of MCW and AFW, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Trip to Japan, 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Topical file
      - "The Clabaughs, with a special chapter on Henry Haggard (1746-1842), " by Betty Harrell, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Historical and Family Documents from the Lives of Mary Clabaugh Wright (1917-1970) & Arthur Frederick Wright (1913-1976)"
    Photocopies of original correspondence and printed materials were compiled into nineteen volumes by Charles Duncan Wright and Jonathan Arthur Wright, sons of Arthur and Mary Wright, in 2004-2006. There is duplication of material within the bound volumes. Items were not always bound in chronological order as indicated by volume titles.
    - Vol. I: Family Roots of Arthur Frederick Wright, c. 1650-1913 and Vol. 2: Family Roots of Mary Clabaugh Wright Prior to 1917 (bound together) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Vol. 3: Mary Clabaugh Wright, The Early Years, 1917-1940 and Vol. 4: Arthur Frederick Wright, The Early Years, 1913-1940 (bound together) (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volume 3, 1930-1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volume 4, 1934-1940 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Vol. 5: September 1940 (Japan) to June 1941 (Peking) and Vol. 6: June 1941 (Peking) to March 1943 (bound together) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volume 5, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volume 6, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Vols. 7 and 8: Weihsien, China, March 1943 to October 1945 (bound together) (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Materials to be interfiled in volume 7, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volume 7, 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Vol. 8 (cont'd): October 1945 to Late 1947 (Peking), Vol. 9: The Early Stanford Years, Late 1947 to 1952, and Vol. 10: Japan, 1952-1953 (bound together) (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volumes 8-10, 1945-1954 (Box 5, Folder 5-7)
    - Vol. 11: Mary Clabaugh Wright, The Family Years, 1954-1970, Vol. 12: Arthur Frederick Wright, The Family Years, 1954-1976, and Vol. 13: Various Documents, 1962-1986 (bound together) (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Originals and photocopies used in volumes 11-13, 1954-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Vol. 14: Additional Documents, Arthur Frederick Wright, 1913-1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Vol. 15: Additional Documents, Mary Clabaugh Wright, 1917-1940
      - Parts A-B (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
      - Part C (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Vol. 16: Additional Documents, Arthur Frederick Wright & Mary Clabaugh Wright, Japan and China, 1940-1954 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 17: Additional Documents, Parts A-C, Mary Clabaugh Wright, 1954-1970 (Box 7, Folder 3-5)
    - Vol. 18: Additional Documents, Arthur Frederick Wright, 1954-1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Vol. 19: Additional Documents, Parts A-B, Papers from Betty Johnson (Box 8, Folder 2-3)